Finding Aid for the Michael and Susan Kahn Collection of Political Cartoons LSC.2419
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 5. International Art, Prints, Broadsides and Ephemera, 1690-2010; Series 5; 21.9 linear feet (13 boxes, 1 map folder)
  - Les Beaux Jours de la Vie. Un Paiement de Dividende, 1845; 1 Print. FRAMED (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - The New Hannoveraner: City of the World Exposition (From South to North), 2000; Large poster previously rolled. Small pin holes in corners. (Folder 507)
    Hannover, Germany was the host city for the World Exposition in 2000.
  - 19th International Nasreddin Hodja Cartoon Contest, 1999; Large poster. Some wear and tear from rolling, folding and small holes in corner from previous display. (Folder 507)
  - Hasta que la Vida Nos Separe, circa 1990; 1 Poster (Folder 507)
  - Sharply Drawn - The Political Cartons of Louis Raemaekers: 1914-1941, 2007; 1 Poster (Folder 507)
  - Chillico art, circa 2020; 2 small posters with different designs, previously rolled and folded. (Folder 507)
    César Aguilar-Peña creates cartoons under the name Chillico.
  - Monos y Monadas: Semanario Festivo, 2001; 1 Poster (Folder 507)
  - Daumier: The Uprising, 2000; 1 Poster (Folder 507)
  - Bienvenido Amor, circa 1990; 1 Poster (Folder 507)
  - Nicolas Yerovi El unico Periodista que Miente con Franqueza, circa 1985; 1 Poster (Folder 507)
  - Picasso's Paintings, Watercolors, Drawings and Sculpture - A Comprehensive Catalogue 1885-1973: Spanish Civil War 1937-1939, 1995; 1 Poster (Folder 507)
  - The Tea Tax Tempest, Or, the Anglo-American Revolution, circa 1781; 1 Engraving. Some discoloration, staining, tears. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    A satirical, contemporary view point from Continental Europe, showing figures in the foreground representing the world watching and opining on the events of the American Revolution (shown projected in the background by a teapot). Attributed to Carl Guttenberg.
  - A Big Thing On Ice: The Hobby Horse Tournament, 1889; 1 Lithograph. Tinted lithograph. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    A Big Thing On Ice: The Hobby Horse Tournament is a cartoon by John Wilson Bengough that was published in 1889 in the Montreal Star's Winter Carnival supplement (Montreal, Canada). The Montreal Winter Carnival Ice Hockey Tournaments were held 1883-1889 and are considered to be some of the first tournaments held in the sport of hockey.
  - [Chinese print with Chinese text and approximately 100 captioned caricature faces. A pen nib seems to be impaling some heads.], circa 1975; 1 Print. Cream colored paper with black ink. (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - [Chinese print with three frames showing caricatures, text and drawings including pen nibs and ink.], circa 1975; 1 Print (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - [Japanese print with some text, includes warrior holding a sword], circa 1990; 1 Print. Cream colored fabric-like paper mat with print adhered. Hand-colored print with some text in black and red stamped text characters. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    Japanese print of unknown artist and title. Some text. Includes warrior (samurai?) in motion holding a sword in right hand, a small yellow bird flies above his sword.
  - A Harlot's Progress Plate 1 / Wm Hogarth inv't pinx't et sculp!, 1733; 1 Engraving (Box 75, Folder 2)
    William Hogarth was an English painter, printmaker and political satirist. The "A Harlot's Progress" series is one of Hogarth's most notable.
    William Hogarth's A Harlot's Progress charts the unfortunate fall of the likeable Moll Hackabout from pretty young ingénue to prostitute after her arrival in London. First appearing as a series of paintings, it was then reproduced as engraved prints. (Source: British Library)
  - A Harlot's Progress Plate 6 / W.m Hogarth inv't pinx't et sculp!, 1733; 1 Engraving (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - A Harlot's Progress Plate 5 / W.m Hogarth inv't pinx't et sculp!, 1733; 1 Engraving (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - A Harlot's Progress Plate 4 / W.m Hogarth inv't pinx't et sculp!, 1733; 1 Engraving (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - A Harlot's Progress Plate 2 / W.m Hogarth inv't pinx't et sculp!, 1733; 1 Engraving (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - A Harlot's Progress Plate 3 / W. Hogarth inv't pinx't et sculp!, 1733; 1 Engraving (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Exact position of the Indian editors: Sword of Democles always hanging over the heads of those who control the "Free Press in India", 1894, August 5; 1 Lithograph. Adhered to mat boards. (Box 75, Folder 3)
    Published during the British Raj (1858-1947).
    Depicts a scene of government censorship of the press in India during British Raj.
  - The drainage tax... Govt official: Away with these bunds, chaprasi, let out these stagnant waters off these fields..., 1894, August 19; 1 Lithograph. Adhered to mat boards. (Box 75, Folder 3)
    Commentary on India's government regulations on stagnant water compromising crop yield during British Raj.
  - [Vietnamese prints from Vietnam War period or post Vietnam War], circa 1969; 11 Prints. Prints left in original plastic with backing board due to identifying information on labels. (Box 76, Folder 13)
    Set of 11 propaganda style posters, possibly created in North Vietnam to commemorate end of war or possibly reprints. Captions from verso of prints: (1) 30 years (2) The US Road during the 1967 dry season in South Vietnam (3) Poster 63 (4) 4,000 corpses of the American planes (5) North Vietnam (6) Is this Nixon's military target? (7) 34 B-52 Stratofortresses were shot down by the people and army in the North, Nixon suffering headache due to VIetnam War (8) Warmly welcome the resounding victory of the people and army in the North shot down 1,500 US war planes (9) Determined to harvest a great Winter-Spring crop Militiawomen exterminate the USAF (10) Enemy destroys - we march forward (11) Shattering the American B-52 campaign engraving in our bones
  - Judith an Oratorio of Sacred Drama by .... The World Shall Bow to the Abyssinian Throne, circa 1732; 1 Engraving (Box 76, Folder 2)
    William Hogarth was an English painter, printmaker and political satirist.
  - Datur vacuum, 1736; 1 Engraving (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - The Bench... of the different meaning of the words Character, Caracatura and Outre in Painting and Drawing, 1758; 1 Engraving (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Duke William's Ghost, 1799 May 7; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    James Gillray was a British caricaturist and engraver who, along with William Hogarth, is regarded as one of the most important and influential political cartoonists. His work was very popular in its time and was typically sold at the London shop of his publisher Hannah Humphrey.
  - The Castle in the Moon: a new adventure not mentioned by Cervantes., 1782 August 22; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Swearing to the Cutting Monster or --- A Scene in Bow Street, circa 1849; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    Reprint of 1790 work. Verso of backing mat which was removed during preparing collection to ship states "Gillray Reprint, 1849"; originally published May 20, 1790.
  - An Old English Gentleman pester'd by Servants wanting Places. [copy 2], 1809 May 16; 1 Etching (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - John Bull and the Sinking Fund -- a Petty scheme for Reducing the Taxes & paying off the National Debt!, 1807 February 29; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - The Reconciliation. -- "And he arose and came to his Father, and his Father saw him, & had compassion, & ran & fell on his Neck, & kissed him. -- Read the Parable Verse 16 to 24., 1804 November 20; 1 Etching (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Armed-Heroes, 1803 May 18; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - The Man of Feeling in search of Indispensibles; -- a Scene at the Little French Milleners., 1800 February 12; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - The Reception in Holland, 1799 September 8; 1 Etching (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Jove in His Chair, 1782 September 11; 1 Etching (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - John Bull & his Dog Faithful... Among the Faithless Faithful Only Found., 1796 April 20; 1 Etching. Hand-colored etching. (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Leveling; Alliance a la Francoise; -- or -- The Union of the Coronet & Clyster-pipe., 1796 March 4; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print adhered to paper. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    James Gillray was a British caricaturist and engraver who, along with William Hogarth, is regarded as one of the most important and influential political cartoonists. Gillray's work was very popular in its time and was typically sold at the London shop of his publisher Hannah Humphrey.
  - Patriots amusing themselves; -- or -- Swedes practicing at a Post., 1792 April 19; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Verso has two black and white prints, also by Gillray and published by Humphrey in 1792 "A Uniform Whig" and "Her Royal Highness the Duchess of York." (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - The Balance of Power. Or "The Posterity of the Immortal Chatham, turnd posture master." vide Sherridan's speech [hand-colored version], 1791 April 21; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    Satire of William Pitt's Russian Policy regarding the balance of power with Russia and Turkey. Figures featured in the illustration are: Prime Minister William Pitt the Younger, Ottoman Sultan Selim III, Catherine II (the Great) of Russia and member of Parliament Richard Brinsley Sheridan.
  - Bologna-Sausages, or Opposition Flux'd, 1788 December 12; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Sawney in the Bog-House, 1779 June 4; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    Attributed to James Gillray.
  - "Praetor-urbanus;"-- Inauguration of the Coptic Mayor of Cairo, preceded by the Procurer de la Commune., 1799 March 12; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    Etched by Js. Gillray, from the Original Intercepted Drawing.
  - HB Sketches No. 772: Three United-States-Men. Scene, Piccadilly., 1843 April 20; 1 Lithograph (Box 76, Folder 4)
    John Doyle was born in Dublin and worked in London as a caricaturist, portrait lithographer and painter. From 1829-1851, Doyle published political cartoons anonymously as H.B. Political Sketches. According to Wiki, they were published monthly while Parliament was in session. See National Portrait Gallery description: https://www.npg.org.uk/collections/search/set/392/Political+Sketches+by+H.B.+%28vol+I%29
  - HB Sketches No. 757: Bellerophon in danger!, 1843 February; 1 Lithograph (Box 76, Folder 4)
    John Doyle was born in Dublin and worked in London as a portrait lithographer. From 1829-1851, Doyle published political cartoons anonymously as H.B. Political Sketches. See National Portrait Gallery description: https://www.npg.org.uk/collections/search/set/392/Political+Sketches+by+H.B.+%28vol+I%29
  - HB Sketches No. 752: Curious Inns and Outs or the Disputed Thunder!, 1843; 1 Lithograph (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - HB Sketches No. 725: Modern Phoenix. The bird wot exists single and rises again out of its own ashes., 1842 March 26; 1 Lithograph (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - HB Sketches No. 456: Irish Poucha! or Hase of the Fairies. Vide Heath's Picturesque Annual for 1837., 1836 December 1; 1 Lithograph (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - HB Sketches No. 265: A Picturesque Illustration of an Elegant Simile by HB., 1833 June 5; 1 Etching (Box 76, Folder 4)
    Depicts a well-dressed man holding up his fists in fighting posture, jumping from "Ireland" frying pan into "Colonies" fire below.
  - Brittania's Suitors or The deadly sins of lust, pride, avarice & sloth failing to converge, 2001; 1 Print. Inscribed. (Box 76, Folder 5, Item 17)
    Martin Rowson is a British editorial cartoonist born in 1959. Rowson is a contributor to The Guardian, the Daily Mirror and other publications.
  - Scene From The Grand Christmas Pantomime Now Acting By His Majesty's Servants, circa 1835; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - Drowning Men Catch At Straws, circa 1835; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - The Battle of the Cataplasm, 1773 February 3; 1 Etching (Box 76, Folder 5, Item 4)
    One of a series of illustrations to the novel The Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, Gentleman by Laurence Sterne, published in nine volumes, 1759-1767.
    Depicts a scene of a woman standing near a baby in a cradle, holding her nose in one hand and a candle in the other. She is facing two men. A quote is written below attributed to "Vide Tris Shandy Vol. 4", referring to the novel The Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, Gentleman by Laurence Sterne, published in nine volumes 1759-1767.
  - Wit's Last Stake. Or the Cobling Voters and Abject Canvassers., 1784 April 22; 1 Etching (Box 76, Folder 5, Item 5)
    This work not listed in "Account of Gillray's Caricatures" (Wright & Evans). Met Museum record indicates this is by T. Rowlandson not Gillray as seller's note indicates.
  - Modern Tourists, 1835 August 1; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 76, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - Nixon phả trã nợ máu, circa 1969; 1 Print (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Ta nhất định thắng, circa 1969; 1 Print (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - My God America, What Have You Done?, 2004 April 11; 1 Digital print (Box 76, Folder 7, Item 10)
    A man with a mustache, wearing a beret, stands in Europe looking across the ocean toward the U.S.A. as a giant sloth-like creature labeled The Christian Right seems to be devouring the entire country, dripping liquid and holding a small cross in its right hand. He thinks "My God, America. What have you done?"
  - Our Birmingham Method [along with] A Very Modern Moses, circa 1900 July 21; July 23; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - The Sort of Inquiry He Means [along with] An International Wayside Inn, circa 1900 July 6-7; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Through the Birmingham Looking-Glass [along with] Two Broken Strings, circa 1900 October 6-7; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - "Our Joe" [along with] The Unhappy Child, circa 1900 November 12; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - "Arthur and Joseph" [along with] A Little Jealousy, circa 1900 March 26-27; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - The Unknown Abyss [along with] Te(a) Amo, circa 1900 May 1; May 4; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - The Good Old Days of Protection [along with] The Law of Progress, circa 1900 May 21-22; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Mum's the Word [along with] I Mean to Lead, circa 1900 October 2; October 5; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Relief at Last [along with] A Lecture on Tactics, circa 1900 March 30; April 2; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - The Chef and the Duke [along with] His First Smoke, circa 1900 July 2-3; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - A Prop [along with] Better Than Park Lane, circa 1900 January 23; January 27; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Batting the Dear-Food Hook [along with] Shivering on the Brink, circa 1900 June 4-5; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - The German Bogey [along with] A Dual Ducal Entity, circa 1900 July 24 [July 21?]; July 27; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - The Joe-O'-Lantern [along with] Mr. Facing-Both-Ways, circa 1900 July 17; July 20; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - The Old Properties [along with] Joseph's Dream, circa 1900 July 8-9; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - The Same Trick -- 1900 and 1903 [along with] Taking Him On, circa 1900 September 22; September 24; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - The "Prodigious" Children [along with] His Old Dutch, circa 1900 April 16; April 20; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Proud and Stiff (with apologies to Sir John Tenniel) [along with] The Mourner, circa 1900 April 22-23; 1 two-sided print. (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Uncorking old sherry., 1805 March 10; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Two Pair of Portraits; --- presented to all the unbiased Electors of Great Britain, by John Horne Tooke, 1798 December 1; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - [A Bad Judas?] Thro excedenz herr Oswald von Stroblbardt Injuriarum Licentiatus... [A Bad Judas?], circa 1700; 1 Print. Ink on paper. Some foxing. (Box 78, Folder 1)
    Probably German or Austrian.
  - Don Miguel Zorrero Tuerto Cavellero de las Trencadas... [A Spanish Adventurer?], circa 1700; 1 Print. Ink on paper. Some foxing. (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - The Bear and his Leader --- "what tho I am Obligated to Dance a Bear, a Man be a Gentleman for all that. My bear ever dance to the Gentleelest of tunes., 1806; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - A French Gentleman, of the Court of Louis XVIth. A F(r)ench Gentlemaman, of the Court of Egalite 1799, circa 1799; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    Slightly different than version seen in catalogs online. Some differences: captions below rather than above/within the work; use of "Gentlemaman" word for blue coated figure; different publisher. British Museum: https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/P_1851-0901-994
  - The Bishop of a Tun's Breeches; or The Flaming Eveque purifying the House of Office..., 1851; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    Originally published May 14, 1792. This is an 1851 print.
  - An Old English Gentleman pester'd by Servants wanting Places. [copy 1], 1809 May 16; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - New dramatic resource --- a begging we will go! --- a scene from Covent Garden Theatre after the Conflagration..., 1809 January 15; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    Covent Garden Theatre was burned down on 20 Sept. 1808. The Duke of Northumberland offered Kemble a loan of £10000 on his bond, which was returned to be destroyed at the dinner held to celebrate the laying of the foundation stone of the new theater on 30 Dec. 1808. (Source: V&A Museum, See: Related Materials)
  - Delicious Dreams--Castles in the Air--Glorious Prospects, 1808 April 10; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. One copy is smaller with pencil markings. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Making Decent -- ie -- Broad-bottomites getting into the Grand Costume, 1806 February 20; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - A Cockney & his wife going to Wycombe..., 1805 June 10; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    A picture of Cockney life at the beginning of the present century. (Source: Accounts of Gillray's Caricatures, Wright and Evans)
  - The King of Brobdingnag and Gulliver. Vide - Swifts Gulliver's Voyage to Brobdingnag [copy 1], 1803 June 26; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - The Three Mr. Wiggins's cartoon., 1803 June 16; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Advantages of wearing Muslin Dresses! --- dedicated to the serious attention of the Fashionable Ladies of Great Britain, 1802 February 15; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Buonaparte leaving Egypt..., 1800 March 8; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    A satirical representation of an event which changed the face of events in France and throughout Europe. The designation of "The Deserter of the Army of Egypt," here applied to the hero of Egypt was echoed by many of his countrymen. (Source: Accounts of Gillray's Caricatures, Wright and Evans)
  - The Apples and the Horse-Turds; -- or -- Buonoparte among the Golden Pippins., 1800 February 24; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Consequences of a Successful French Invasion --- Me teach de English Republican to work., 1798 March 1; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Thirty Years have I lived in the parish of Covent Garden and nobody can say -- Mistress Cole -- why did you so?..., 1797 December 16; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    Writing on verso of print indicates subject of illustration may be Napoleon. Accounts of Gillray's Caricatures, Wright and Evans, does not refer to Napoleon.
  - Bank Notes. Paper Money. French Alarmists. O the Devil, the Devil! Ah! Poor John Bull!!!, 1797 March 1; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    Slightly different than version seen in catalogs online. Some differences: captions written in different hand?; publisher different.
  - The Daily Advertiser --- vide. Dundee's speech in the House of Commons 1797..., 1797 January 23; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Dumourier dining in State at St. James's on the 15 May, 1793., 1793 March 30; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - A picturesque view of the state of the nation for February 1778, circa 1778 March; 1 Engraving (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Lubber's Hole... alias The Crack'd Jordan., 1791 November 1; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - The Balance of Power. Or "The Posterity of the Immortal Chatham, turnd posture master." vide Sherridan's speech, 1791 April 21; 1 Etching. Ink on paper. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - ---"Oh! Listen to the Voice of Love., 1799 November 14; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - The Infrnals choice or the man of the people below stairs, 1784 April 12; 1 Etching. Ink on paper. (Box 78, Folder 4, Item 7)
    The British Museum record (AN81135001) description: Fox is being chaired by demons, who advance toward flames (left) in which stands a devil with a pitch-fork waiting to receive him. Fox, seated, holding out his hat, his left hand on his breast says, "Westminster was pretty Hot but this much more so". The demons who support Fox's chair and prance along behind it appear to have been copied from the Devil in BMSat 6283. The foremost has the same twisted ram's horns, the claws of a bird of prey, and barbed tail. He shouts "Fox for Ever." His companions resemble him with slight variations...
  - We are all come: or Scotch Coal burns longer than Pitt or Newcastle Coal, circa 1762; 1 Print. Ink on paper. (Box 78, Folder 4, Item 2)
    Anonymous print satirizing Prime Minister John Stuart, Third Earl of Bute.
  - The State Watchman discovered by the Genius of Britain studying plans for the Reduction of America, 1781 December 10; 1 Etching. Ink on paper. (Box 78, Folder 4, Item 1)
    Unsigned. Attributed to Thomas Rowlandson. See Met Museum record: https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/389049
  - A Toad Under a Harrow, 1829 June 20; 1 Etching. Hand-colored print. Hinging tape adhered from mat removal. (Box 78, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - The Conclusions of the first volume of the Caricature Magazine, 1807 September 1; 1 Etching. Hand-colored etching. (Box 78, Folder 4, Item 5)
  - A Friendly Visit, 1814 April 16; 1 Etching. Hand-colored etching. (Box 78, Folder 4, Item 9)
  - The Sick Lion or the Ungratefull Jack Asses... vide Aesop's fables, 1809 April 10; 1 Print. Hand-colored print. (Box 78, Folder 4, Item 8)
    George Cruikshank was a British caricaturist and book illustrator. His brother was the artist Isaac Robert Cruikshank and their father was notable Scottish artist Isaac Cruikshank.